Purushottam Reddy.M

I have amassed **1.5** years of **full time** and **8** months **internship** experience as a full-stack web developer, with a focus on technologies like **Ruby on Rails**, **React.js**, and **Next.js**. During this period, I have consistently generated code that is both maintainable and efficient, while adhering to industry best practices in both front-end and back-end development.

EXPERIENCE

Bitsila -Future of ONDC, Bengaluru(On-site) -Software engineer

Sep 2023 - Nov 2023 (3 Months)

Responsible for api integrations with external e-commerce like shopify and maintaining internal RestApi exposed to the clients in ROR.

Zolvit (formerly Vakilsearch), Chennai (On-site & Remote) - Associate Software engineer

June 2022 - Aug 2023 (1.3 + Years)

Responsible for maintaining the web application in Ruby on rails for the organization product Libra-The advocate's app.

Responsible for api for an important judgments module for web and mobile application in backend with ruby on rails.

Responsible for various responsive components for customer onboarding to the product (https://vakilsearch.com/) in Next.js.

Zolvit (formerly Vakilsearch), Chennai (On-site) - Intern

Nov 2021 - June 2022 (8 Months)

Responsible for fixing various bugs and new feature developments for product Libra-The advocate's app.

ROLES & RESPONSIBILITIES

Bitsila -Future of Retail | ONDC

- Created Restful API's and integrated third party retail business api's with companies internal api in ROR.

Zolvit

- Successfully carried out a variety of database migrations, which involved implementing functionalities like document bookmarking and searching. These new features were smoothly integrated into the existing frontend workflow, which included tasks such as querying data in MongoDB, filtering and organizing data, and establishing a unified API for the mobile team. Also collaborated with the mobile team to ensure seamless integrations in RoR.
- Worked in various micro-frontends and integrating user tracking with mixpanel, moengage and tracking events in elastic search.
- participated in the development of multiple user onboarding processes, encompassing the entire journey of a user from start to finish. Additionally, I transformed several figma designs into React code and seamlessly integrated them into the user flow's life cycle.
- Created multiple email templates for marketing purposes and optimized various static pages of the website for SEO

Kolimigundla(V), Nandyal(Dist), AP, - 518123 **8008621161** puru13794@gmail.com GitHub LinkedIn

SKILLS

Ruby, Ruby on rails(ROR), javascript (ES6+), Rest Apis, SCSS,SQL,Mongodb,React.js,N ext.js,Css3,Html5,Postgres, Bootstrap, Jquery, Git.

EDUCATION

Vel Tech Rangarajan Dr.Sagunthala R&D Institute of Science and Technology, CSE, chennai -8.3 CGPA

- Feb 2018 - Feb 2022

Narayana Junior College - 94%

- May 2016 – Apr 2018

Keshava Reddy Residential School -9.5 GPA

- May 2016

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent, Telugu -Native, Hindi - Fluent, Tamil proficient